Vivek Kumar

LinkedIn | GitHub |

Location: New Delhi, Delhi, India Email: vivekumar2003bsr@gmail.com | Mobile: +91 - 7088980706

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

I am a highly skilled software developer with over **3 years of experience** in **HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript and Python**. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **React, Angular, and Vue.js** and experience with REST APIs and MVC frameworks. Effective team player with excellent analytical skills, and training potential. Problem-solving and communication skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, HTML, CSS, R, MATLAB

Frameworks : React.js, Next.js, Angular, Express, Node.js

Libraries : Material, Redux, React Router

Databases : MongoDB, MySQL

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Git, Github

EXPERIENCE

Web DeveloperFeb 2023 – Mar 2023Cluster Innovation Centre, DUNew Delhi, Delhi, India

• Designed and Developed for National Seminar on Innovation in Higher Education through Public - Private -

- Partnership Model
- Easy to navigate, despite being a single page
- Engaging and informative with multimedia elements

Full Stack DeveloperDaulatram College, DU

New Delhi, Delhi, India

- Designed and developed dynamic and responsive websites using **MERN Stack** with improved **website Interface**
- Worked with **REST APIs** to retrieve and display data from databases
- Worked with MVC frameworks to develop robust and scalable backends

Full Stack Developer Mar 2021 – Apr 2021

- Created a website named Quick Access App
- Consists of 5 features i.e TO-DO list, Calculator, Calendar, Music player, Weather, and prediction of the humidity in a city
- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, Reactjs, MongoDB, NodeJs, and ExpressJs

EDUCATION

Cluster Innovation Centre, University of Delhi

B. Tech (IT and MI)

New Delhi, Delhi, India

Nov 2020 – Aug 2024

C.G.P.A – 8.88

Kendriya Vidyalaya, BulanshahrBulandshahr, U.P, India12th (Science Stream with CS)Apr 2019 – May 2020

Percentage - 84.8

Kendriya Vidyalaya, BulanshahrBulandshahr, U.P, India

10th
Apr 2017 – MAy 2018

Percentage - 79.6

BreakIn Backend

NodeJs, ExpressJs, MongoDb, mongoose-GridFs-Storage, Git

Source Code

- This project is a backend for the mobile App for the Users and Owner of the place
- Rest APIs from scratch with the integration of MongoDb
- Storing files in MongoDB using GridFS-Storage
- Authentication with JWT and work with token generation till it's expiration

Covoke 5.0 ReactJs, HTML, CSS, Git Source Code

- This project is made for Tech Fest which organized by our centre
- It is a static-single page website
- · Having Interactive and animations UI

Blood Bank Management System

Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git

Source Code

- This project is to monitor blood bank data, cells, and stocks.
- It manages all the blood banks, donor lists, stocks of blood, and blood group information

<u>Tic-Tac-Toe Game</u>

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Git

Source Code

- Designed Created this game in 3x3 grid using Min-Max Algorithm
- Tried to implement in higher order grid as well

Facial Expression Recognition

Python, Scikit-learn, PyTorch, Git

Source Code

- · Made Hybrid Model of CNN-KNN to Facial Expression Recognition
- · Holds strong emotion recognition capabilities and would be able to comprehend people
- · Also it will communicate with them more naturally

Quizstar Python, Tkinter, Git

Source Code

- Made a GUI fun Quiz game with Tkinter
- · Having some questions on the space theme and you have answer
- · Calculate Score on the basis of your performance and give you remark

Computer Graphics Programs

Python, OpenGL, Git

Source Code

- Made so many programs as Computer Graphics with OpenGL and Tkinter
- Having some extraordinary results

CERTIFICATIONS

- Entrepreneurship Awareness Drive by the E-Cell IIT Kharagpur
- Web Development Course 2.0
- HTML and CSS Certification